<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ITER</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_activity_student">Student Clubs</string>
    <string name="title_activity_notice">Notice</string>
    <string name="title_activity_placement">Placement</string>
    <string name="str_btn_start">Start SlideShow</string>
    <string name="str_btn_stop">Stop SlideShow</string>
    <string name="placmnt1">Ever since its inception, the Placement Cell of ITER has created its impression by striking a right balance between academics and industry.It strongly believes in the adage,Nothing less than the industry best. Its constant endeavour in preparing its graduating engineers and MCA graduates in the field of technology has been an epitome of success over a period of time.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_newsnd_event">NewsndEvent</string>
    <string name="title_activity_facilities">Facilities</string>
    <string name="hostel">The Institution provides facilities for hostel accommodation for both boys and girls. The hostels are spacious, safe and secured with a cordial environment and surrounded by pleasant landscapes. A hygienic kitchen has been provided in each hostel with large dining halls. The rooms are well furnished. ITER has three in-campus girls hostels accommodating one thousand students. Both the hostels have round the clock Wi-Fi connectivity and medical facility. Similarly, ITER has six boys hostels accommodating one thousand students. Proper hygienic condition and strict supervision is maintained throughout.</string>
    <string name="transportation">ITER has its dedicated transport for the day scholars, covering entire Bhubaneswar. Route plans are chalked out keeping in mind the convenience of the students. The institute has deployed twelve medium sized buses so as to save time for students in commuting to and from the institute. PERSONALITY DEVELOPMENT and COMMUNICATION SKILLS The Institute makes all out efforts to bring-out the hidden talents of the students and nourish in them leadership qualities, excellent communication skills and a developed personality, so that they grow up as professionals of global standards to flourish in professional career.</string>
    <string name="yoga">Holding of regular yoga sessions and meditation practices are also a feature to encourage students for developing their individual talent and health. This is also aimed at building their positive attitude and providing them relief from feelings of burden and disappointment, if any.</string>
    <string name="multigym">The gym has latest equipments aided by trainers and physiotherapists for guided exercise for students and staff.</string>
    <string name="antiwomen">As made mandatory by law an anti women harassment cell is functioning in SOA University with a senior professor as Chairperson and other senior faculty members as members. The Cell is empowered to look into all forms of harassment against women and recommend appropriate sanctions.</string>
    <string name="antiragging">As per Honble Supreme Courts judgement the institute ensures a ragging free environment both inside the academic premises and hostels. An anti-ragging cells under the Chairmanship of Prof. (Dr.) B.K. Sarap functions for the prevention of ragging in all its forms. Further, the Cell has senior faculty members as members who counsel the students to be aware of Honble Supreme Courts judgement and how to abide by it.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_department">Department</string>
    <string name="title_activity_humanity">HUMANITY</string>
    <string name="title_activity_civil">CE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cse">CSE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_csit">CSIT</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ee">EE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_eee">EEE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_ece">ECE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_eice">EICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_eie">EIE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mech">MECH</string>
    <string name="title_activity_c">CA</string>
    <string name="cse">Computers and networking have changed the way we looked at the world. The importance of Computer Science and Engineering would increase in coming days and remain indispensable to all other branches of knowledge, engineering, medical sciences and aerospace etc. The Department has been contributing critically to teaching learning process, research and collaborations. Computer Science and Engineering students are involved in the study of hardware infrastructure – computers, networks, embedded devices, as well as operating systems, compilers and networking software. The focus is on the understanding of cooperation between hardware and software to yield an optimal performance.The department aims at technical and professional competency in Computer Science and Engineering and also aids in inculcating moral and ethical values. The alacrity of the students to learn makes it easier for the department of Computer Science and Engineering to produce top-notch engineers who are being recruited by companies all over India. This branch now is the epicenter of all other branches and offers the sought after courses by the under graduate and post graduate programme. The department currently offers: B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering Dual Degree in Engineering (B.Tech and M.Tech) Dual Degree in Management (B.Tech and MBA) M.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering M.Tech in Computer Science and Data Processing Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering. The B.Tech. programme offered by this branch has been accredited by the National Board of Accreditation (NBA), AICTE, Since its inception, the department has always been recognized all over for excellence in teaching and research. Graduates of the department entertain the best placement profile in the institute, with an equal preference from industry as well as academic. All over the world, exstudents of the Department occupy top positions in both academic and industry. The institute has tie up with several industries like Infosys, TCS and Hexaware and others to help the students to becomeindustry ready. Department promotes and harnesses the research initiatives by its faculty members as well as the researchers in various domains of Computer Science and Engineering like Ad hoc Networks, Artificial Intelligence, Soft Computing and Machine Learning, Data mining, Bioinformatics, Computer Networking, Computational Finance and Cloud Computing etc.</string>
    <string name="civil">Colossal innovations in micro and macro structural designs and the introduction of new materials have revolutionized the oldest branch of engineering i.e. Civil Engineering. The expanse of Civil Engineering today, assimilates other branches of engineering and specialized areas due to the sophistication of designs and construction. The Department of Civil Engineering reflects the contemporary trends in the offered programmes : B.Tech in Civil Engineering Dual Degree in Civil Engineering Dual Degree in Civil Engineering and Management M.Tech. in Structural Engineering M.Tech. in Geotechnical Engineering Ph.D. Programme in Civil Engineering To facilitate the teaching learning process experienced faculty members with required qualification and consistent research activities, create an open and innovative ambience for the students. The focus is on students’ understanding of theoretical concepts and frameworks and intensive application training in laboratories. This is further supplemented by taking the students for industrial exposure and field study. The following laboratories have been set up for training, research and development with environmental safeguards : Geo-Technical Engineering Laboratory Transportation Engineering Laboratory Concrete Laboratory Environmental Engineering Research Laboratory Surveying Laboratory Computational Laboratory Structural Engineering Laboratory Fluid Mechanics Laboratory Water Resource Engineering Laboratory Advanced Research Laboratory Hydro-Meteorological Laboratory</string>
    <string name="ca">"The Department recognizes teaching as a holistic activity and development of human resources for the service of the nation. Computer Application is a pre-condition to build integrity, creativity and freedom of academic experiment for new technology and dissemination of research findings. The motivating environment enlivens the spirits of students and the efficacy of faculty strengthens the quest for quality education. The Department is also engaged in advanced research having an enrolment of M.Tech and Ph.D. candidates. FEATURES A well-furnished and well-equipped library updated every year with new books. The Department has laboratories with adequate number of computers and centrally connected to the Institute's server carry out programmes and projects of the curriculum and innovative experiments in different environments like Windows 7, Red Hat Linux and Ubuntu10 along with research tools like Latex, NS2, MatLab are present. A smart seminar hall with DLP and interactive audio system. Highly efficient and dynamic training and placement cell, imparting personality development and personnel management skill."</string>
    <string name="csit">Computer Science and Information Technology introduced the data, information and knowledge to the internet superhighways, making this world a global village. Humanity is inevitably dependent on it. As a branch of engineering, its relevance will continue to grow in future. This Department offers M.Tech programme in Computer Science and Informatics. It is well equipped with adequate laboratory infrastructure and necessary staff strength. The Department emphasizes on interactive teaching and research and thus caters to the computational needs of students and faculty members. The Department has lab facility to train the students in different specialized areas such as Web Technology, Advance Java Platform, Networking, Multimedia and popular programming languages. The labs are connected to the networking environment with state-of-theart servers with emphasis on software engineering, software to make the students industry adaptable. Software application packages like Visual Studio, ORACLE 11g, SQL SERVER, LINUX, MATLAB-7 and programming suites like C, C++ and JAVA are made available to all students and staff. The laboratories have high-end servers, including Linux/Unix and Windows platforms. Each lab session in all the semesters has been meticulously designed in the form of assignments, which are to be completed within stipulated time. Appropriate lab procedures are followed to get the right kind of hands-on-experience and expertise in the above said software. The Department also offers special training to the students in .NET, Core JAVA, Advance Java and various internet tools. This helps them in preparing good projects in the areas of Mining, Tourism, Air Ticket Reservation, Web Based Network Programming and Security Marketing Application, Healthcare System and Online Examination, Adhoc Networks etc. The Institute has tie-up with several Industries like Infosys, TCS, Hexaware and others to help the students to be industry ready. The Department also offers industrial electives as a part of the course curriculum in which recent advancement in IT is being imparted. Programmes Offered B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (4 years) M.Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering (2 years) M.Tech in Computer Science and Data Processing (2 years) Dual Degree in Engineering (B.Tech. and M.Tech.) Dual Degree in Management (B.Tech. and MBA) Ph.D.</string>
    <string name="ece">The Department of Electrical Instrumentation and Control Engineering offers the 4-years B.Tech Programme in Electrical Instrumentation and Control Engineering. The Institute of Technical Education and Research has been offering this course since 2008. Electrical Instrumentation and Control is a vast interdisciplinary branch of engineering. The department is fascinating motley of multifarious disciplines of technology such as electronic, electrical and mechanical engineering as a response to the sophistication of industrial operations. With growing automation of manufacturing, nuclear power generation and many other conventional production systems, Instrumentation and Control Engineering has a challenging responsibility of designing and developing reliable control systems. The department, a relatively new branch of engineering, attracts a large number of undergraduate students due to its contemporary relevance. The department with its state of the art laboratories and dynamic faculties are involved in providing quality education. The laboratories are well maintained and are regularly updated responding to the changing needs of the university syllabus and technological scenario.</string>
    <string name="ee">As a core branch the department lives up to the developments taking place in the field of electricity eneration through hydro, thermal, nuclear and nonconventional sources. The department teaches distribution of electricity and use of new materials for different applications. The students get ample scope of learning modern technology with the help of qualified teachers. The department has been re-accredited by NBA, AICTE. Eminent professors are engaged in quality research and supervision of Ph.D. scholars. The department has specific laboratories for Basic Electrical Engineering, Network Devices, Electrical Machines-I and II, Control and Instrumentation, Power Systems, Power Electronics, Electric Drives, Electrical Design and Simulation, Project Laboratories. A Computational Laboratory has been added to the department for carrying out Computer Aided research activities. Modernization and Removal of Obsolescence(MODROB) is regularly practiced in all the laboratories. A Robotics Laboratory is expected to function shortly. Basic Electrical Engineering and Network Devices Laboratory is meant for verification of Basic Principles of Electrical Engineering and Laws of Electrical Networks. The Machine Lab is well equipped with modern electrical machines : single and three phase transformers with multi winding, DC and AC Motor Generator Sets, Induction and Synchronous Motors and Single Phase Motors to name a few. The Control and Instrumentation Lab. has Amplidyne Set, DC Position Control System, Data Acquisition System, PID Controller etc. The Power Electronics Lab. is equipped with Converter Rectifiers and Inverters both single phase and three phase, Cyclo Converter, IGBTbased Inverter and other modern equipment in related field. The Power System Lab is equipped with Relay Trainers, Oil Testing Kit, Current Injection Circuit, Artificial Transmission Line etc. The Power System Lab. is being augmented with advanced relay and protection systems, relevant power system software. The Laboratory will be having state of the art technology. The aim is to develop a knowledge intensive laboratory keeping in mind the need of theindustry with high competence levels. The laboratory helps in promoting research work for PG students and faculties. Renewable Energy Laboratory has already been set up for M.Tech. students. An advanced laboratory equipped with modern instruments is under preparation for M.Tech. students. Further, a new lab of High Voltage Engineering has been set up in viewof the requirement of the industry. The laboratory facilitates high voltage testing of electrical equipments. The Department has its own computer lab to facilitate Computer Aided Electrical Machine Design, software based project work for final year Under Graduate students, students in the Post Graduate Program. This lab also promotes the faculty members for in-house Research and Development programme. The Department has its own Library having referred texts of international repute for faculty members and students. Interested faculties are regularly sponsored to carry out Post Graduate and Doctoral research programs in reputed institute outside SOA University. The department has the necessary facilities to carryout doctoral work. A large number of faculty members have been engaged in carrying out their doctoral work.</string>
    <string name="eee">The Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering, ITER, SOA University, Bhubaneswar was started in the year 2006. It offers one Under-Graduate programme (B.Tech.), one Post-Graduate programme (M.Tech.) in Power Systems and Power Electronics) and also research programmes (Ph.D.) in the various fields of Electrical and Electronics Engineering. Today, the department has grown not only in terms of student and faculty strength, but also in improving the laboratory facilities for the teaching and research purposes. Our Department is dedicated to the current needs of industry with flexibility to tune its progamme according to different requirements. The Department has more than ten well equipped, state of the art, laboratories in the major areas of Electrical and Electronics Engineering and extends sufficient computing and library facilities. The dedicated staff members have sound knowledge in emerging areas like embedded systems, power electronics applications in power systems and sustainable energy, etc. The breadth and depth of the research interests of the academic staff ensures a high standard of lecture courses and provides excellent opportunities for challenging and stimulating projects and thesis work. The faculty and students participate in National and International conferences and publish numerous papers every year in reputed journals. In order to improve the quality of man power, periodic training programmes are being conducted by inviting eminent personalities from Industry and Academic Institutions and sponsoring the faculty for various Faculty Development Programmes.</string>
    <string name="eice">Instrumentation and control engineering play a vital role in any modern industry. We aim at producing talented instrumentation and control specialists who cater to the needs of the modern industries. The department is a fascinating motley of multifarious disciplines of technology such as Electronics, Electrical, and Mechanical Measurements, Process Control Engineering. The curriculum begins with foundation courses in mathematics, physics, chemistry, electronics and mechanics. Emphasis is laid on the courses like Sensors and Transducers, Micro-controllers, Industrial Instrumentation, Control Systems, PC interfacing and Telemetry. The focus in the final year is more on advanced electives such as Instrumentation System Design, Robotics, Intelligent Controllers, Embedded Systems, and Instrumentation and control systems for industries. With a prefect blend of industrial exposure, coupled with good technical base, our students will make their presence felt in various technological domains in all the top-level industries. The Department of Electrical Instrumentation and Control Engineering offers the 4-years B.Tech Programme in Electrical Instrumentation and Control Engineering. The Institute of Technical Education and Research has been offering this course since 2008. Electrical Instrumentation and Control is a vast interdisciplinary branch of engineering. The department is fascinating motley of multifarious disciplines of technology such as electronic, electrical and mechanical engineering as a response to the sophistication of industrial operations. With growing automation of manufacturing, nuclear power generation and many other conventional production systems, Instrumentation and Control Engineering has a challenging responsibility of designing and developing reliable control systems. The department, a relatively new branch of engineering, attracts a large number of undergraduate students due to its contemporary relevance. The department with its state of the art laboratories and dynamic faculties are involved in providing quality education. The laboratories are well maintained and are regularly updated responding to the changing needs of the university syllabus and technological scenario. The laboratories are well maintained and are regularly updated responding to the changing needs of the university syllabus and technological scenario.</string>
    <string name="humanity">Scope is international, our approach interdisciplinary. We work at the intersections of economics, management, language and literature, technical writing. The areas of emphasis include skill development of undergraduate and post-graduate students, awareness-raising exercises, awakening to global trends and diversity of cultures. The Department helps students develop the communicative, analytic and cultural insight to sustain their growth in their personal and professional life. The Department consistently works on innovative ways of training, keeping in focus the varied sensibility of the students. Further, the Department implements valuable inputs from the industry e.g. the Campus-Connect Programme by Infosys. Research scholars enrolled in the Ph.D programme are working on communication studies, language, literature, cultural studies, economics and management. The Department of Humanities and Social Sciences has several segments like English, Human Resource Management, Organisational Behaviour and Economics. It has been imperative throughout the world to include components of soft skills, economics and organizational studies in engineering programmes. This gives human face to the use of engineering and technology. The faculty members are engaged in research and their papers have been published in national and international journals of repute. They have also authored books, which have been widely circulated and acclaimed. Four digital communication practice laboratories have been setup. The laboratories are well equipped for language and soft skills development.</string>
    <string name="mech">Mechanical Engineering is always on the edge, moving in new directions and exploring new possibilities. From design, manufacturing and mechanical systems and structures the subject now studies bio-mechanical and biomechatronics. Mechanical engineer today are the forefront of developing new technology for environmental remediation, farming and food production, housing, transportation, safety, security, healthcare and water resources. The Department of Mechanical Engineering is one of the largest in ITER and Odisha. The B.Tech. programme focuses on the study of engineering of sciences, understanding of key concepts, theoretical and experimental solution of physical problems and design of systems relevant to the contemporary industrial needs and challenges. The faculty members are well experienced to sustain a lively and interactive teaching learning process in the class rooms. This approach stimulates the intellectual curiosity and creativity of the students. Similarly, M.Tech. students and Ph.D. scholars work on Refrigeration and Air Conditioning, Heat Transfer, I.C. Engineer, Automobiler, Fluid Mechanics, Hydraulic Machines, Machine Dynamics, Material Testing Material Testing, Applied Mechanics, Control and Measurement, CNC Machining, material science, solar energy, vibration and Bio-Mechanics. The Department has a well equipped workshop and machine shop. The department has also modern facilities for engineering graphics and computational analysis. The Department has licensed software like solid works 2009, Matlab 7.1, Ansys-CFD 14.3 and AutoCAD 2006 for modelling, simulation of real type domain problems. The students are updated with industry based knowledge in computer aided manufacturing laboratory. The departmental library has the latest books/titles from reputed publishers e.g. Elsevier, Springer-Verlag and Taylor-Francis.The department has the access to e-journals of Elsevier,ASME, Springer-Verlag and Taylor-Francis publishers etc which helps our faculty members.</string>
    <string name="eie">Electronics and Instrumentation department is a fusion of electronics with Instrumentation Engineering subjects applied to the field of industrial innovation. The department has been offering UG program and two year PG programs in VLSI and Embedded System as well as microelectronics. All the department programs are AICTE approved and accredited by NBA. Department has well equipped laboratories to give practical training to UG, PG students and for research in chosen areas. The department conducts Institute-Industry interaction along with seminar and conferences regularly for faculty development. Faculties members have published technical papers in peer reviewed journals and also participated in summer schools, workshops, seminars and conferences. Students are provided hands-on training in both the conventional subject as well as in the emerging fields of specialization. The Department is motivated to become a center of excellence in the interdisciplinary fields of Microelectronics, VLSI, Medical Electronics and related emerging areas by producing professionals who excel in Innovation, Entrepreneurship, Creativity, Management and become a responsible Citizen of the society.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_contact">Contact</string>
    <string name="link_text_auto"><b>Call us @:</b>06742351777, 06742351539, 06742350181</string>
    <string name="title_activity_faculty">Faculty</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fce">CE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fc">CA</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fcse">CSE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fcsit">CSIT</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fece">ECE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fee">EE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_feee">EEE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_feice">EICE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_feie">EIE</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fhumanity">HUMANITY</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fmech">MECH</string>
    <string name="title_activity_phy">PHYSICS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maths">MATHS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_chem">CHEMISTRY</string>
    <string name="physics">The history of development of Science and Technology is fascinating. The study of development of basic science and particularly Physics is more fascinating as one can see it to have unraveled a great deal of natures mystery providing insight into the principles and mechanism that ultimately govern sustainable growth of Technology. Each engineering student with a passion to excel in the career needs to undergo a course in Physics at the outset to acquire requisite knowledge on basic principles of nature and inculcate true scientific temper in order to be able to handle complex issues later in the broader field of Technology. Keeping this in view, the course structure in Physics has been designed with emphasis on emerging areas of waves and oscillation, optics, electromagnetism and quantum mechanics. In addition to providing teaching in Physics, the department also imparts teaching in Electrical Engineering Materials (EEM) at B. Tech level and “Introduction to Nanotechnology” at M. Tech level. The Department of Physics has been contributing significantly to quality teaching at B. Tech, M. Tech and Ph.D levels. With as many as nineteen qualified faculty members ably supported by a group of trained and experienced technical staff, the department has earned reputation in academics and has prepared an academic roadmap of its own to attract genuine stakeholders including students, teachers and academicians from other departments of the Institute and those from other Institutes in and outside the state of ODISHA.</string>
    <string name="chemistry">The study of Chemistry and its application is indispensable to the study of engineering and technology. An application oriented understanding of the subject gives the students the leverage to know the artifice of technology. The students acquire the knowledge of chemical compounds and their applications, important especially in electronics, computer engineering and environmental engineering. The Department gives more emphasis on analytical approach, clear theoretical concepts and overall performance of the students in order to achieve academic excellence. The Department has graduated to include studies and research in applied chemistry and environmental science. Department is well equipped with four Chemistry laboratories for B. Tech students. The evaluation of Chemistry laboratory is based on day-to-day performance, viva-voce / quizzes and laboratory test at the end of the semester. B. Tech. students are encouraged to gain more knowledge in the field of chemical technology and environmental engineering. This would make them technically sound and socially aware individuals. Department of Chemistry offers M. Tech. programme in Environmental Science and Technology and Ph. D programme in important areas of Chemical Science and Environmental Science. The Department has customized a functional microbiology laboratory for M. Tech students. The Department is committed to sustain the scientific enquiry of the students and research that is socially beneficial.</string>
    <string name="maths">Mathematics has served humanity as the most powerful tool by solving physical problems of the real and abstract world. It also shows the path to the symmetry of equations in all branches of knowledge. The Department, keeping in view the requirements and future prospects of budding technocrats, has been instrumental in influencing their logical, analytical and computational ability to meet the challenges in the technical field. The curriculum followed by the Department is contemporary and useful for all branches of science and engineering. The faculty of the Department alongwith the research scholars have contributed substantially to different fields of pure and applied mathematics. Major areas of research are Numerical Analysis, Fluid Dynamics, Differential Equations, Operations Research, Estimation Theory and Fuzzy Optimization. The Department has a major contribution in conducting the classes of Ph.D students of the University in all technical branches. The faculty members also take part in the administrative affairs of ITER such as those pertaining to examinations, students welfare, and other extracurricular activities. The Departmental library is well equipped with e-library facilities. Plans are afoot to start postgraduate programmes in emerging fields of Mathematics, Computational Fluid Dynamics, Numerical Optimization and Statistical Analysis.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fchem">CHEMISTRY</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fphy">PHYSICS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fmaths">MATHS</string>
    <string name="title_activity_so">SOA</string>
    <string name="awards">KALIDAS SANMAN:-2009 for outstanding contribution to the filed of technical education in Odisha. EKAMRASHREE AWARD by Ekamra Sanskrutika Prakashani, Bhubaneswar, in 2008 for outstanding contribution to society in the field of education. UTKAL SANMAN by State Council for Artistic Research and Training valuable support and contribution for development of medical education and Health Services in the State of Odisha in 2008. BHAGABAT BEHERA SANMAN for outstanding contribution in the field of Technical Education in Odisha in 2007. SAMAJ O SANSKRUTI SANMAN-2007 for accommodating and educating about 500 students of the local slums of Bhubaneswar.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_inquery">Inquery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_p1">Placement-2013</string>
    <string name="title_activity_p2">Placement-2012</string>
</resources>
